[Music]
he
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome to the ask abijit show I
hope you're all doing great before we
get into the questions let me see who
all is there on the live chat and let me
greet some of you Summit statement
himansu rajpurohit Rich rwi majumdar
Shan rishav Shar Shan chat DSP Swami J
tagat Karan Niha Slayer sakit K katari
jagadish ra meet geopolitics Jagdish
Mali Punjab story DJ Kut trupti pael
philosophic mind Shashank Mister PR Paul
from Kolkata Mr 8ers midnight stalker
rittick sagai vinit sang akit Chan K
Jade Warrior Z6 zuban eung feminist
Slayer geopolitical dub bear D Singh Dr
Atul ravindra Chri utkarsh Z anti broton
proton rakshit Mishra fairy tale
Prashant a fsuk wangu vun Kumar domini
Kumari Ramesh muruga paparo Mansa Prav
Soni inep Sam aara Sagar Chandra Kant
Krishna goind Alfred ragunath from the
suram is Netherlands who else do we have
Krishna prar Gupta St crocodile Baki hna
winter Rangers wolf inquisitive
triangular triangulator Amisha Mishra
atva and everybody else all right all
right all right uh great to have you all
on this live stream and with that said
let's get into the
questions let's take a non-controversial
question to start with shall we are you
sure the controversy will be in question
number two so let's let's start with a
non-controversial question how long and
high can a peacock
fly I've never seen a peacock flying
high or long in the sky I hope this
isn't non-controversial question I'm
sure somebody can create a controversy
out of that as well how long and high
can a peacock fly look as a kid I I have
seen peacocks uh on on trees I've seen
peacocks on the first floor and second
floor of of uh
buildings so from that I can say that a
peacock can probably fly about 100
probably to 100 met High which is about
300 ft most likely I think that's the
ceiling that's a limit as to how high it
can fly and it takes off by jumping with
its feet and flapping its wings and it's
a pretty big bird right the peacock it's
a magnificently beautiful bird the
national bird of India it's about 5 six
kilos in weight pretty dangerous bird if
you are a small animal I once had a cat
who thought that let me go and catch
myself a peacock so he goes after a
peacock and the next thing we know that
he's running the other way the peacock
is after him so peacocks can be like
they are they are Dinosaurs Aren't They
so a peacock can probably fly up to 100
meters high how long can it Fly maybe 2
300 meters I don't think a peock can fly
a kilometer in distance in length so I
think uh how high can it Fly it's about
100 m how long can it Fly maybe about
300 M or if it's really really stressed
out maybe half a kilometer but that's
about it it's not really a bird that's
adapted to
Flying so I hope that's a non-control
controversial question let's take the
controversial one
now so yeah everybody wants to know
about the situation ranir what's your
view about the r situation need to hear
your
take uh what advice will you give does
India really have freedom of
speech are more people people more
focused on him rather than addressing
the already present normalization of
vulgarity and other immoral acts uh what
about the controversy can he come back
and on I mean these are just a few
representative questions there have been
a lot more obviously everybody wants to
know about what I feel about this so uh
as you probably all know many of you
must have discovered me through the
podcast I podcasts I did with ranir I've
done about roughly 30 podcasts I believe
I'm the uh most frequent guest guest on
the rir show and I have known ranir for
several years i' I've spent a lot of
time with him I know him quite well and
of all the people who have expressed
their opinions as experts on this matter
I am probably the person who knows him
the
best and the past week I have been
repeatedly requested to appear on
national TV on those 8:00 p.m. 9:00 p.m.
debates on the big channels you know
which ones the ones that I usually
appear on and I have refused all these
requests I do not want to add more fuel
on the Fire
okay so I have refused to I refused that
multiple times and I said I I told
myself that I will speak about this
after some time has passed and I'll
speak about it at length on this channel
on this show in front of you all not on
something else on some of the platform
so what's happened let's rewind and just
revisit what's happened last weekend I
think on Sunday February 9 or something
uh this a clip started doing the rounds
on social media a clip from uh uh a
person called Samina now I you know you
may not believe it but I had never heard
of Samina before I had never heard of
India's Got latent before this thing
happened I am not into that sort of
stuff I don't watch these comedy shows
and all that I don't find it really I
don't really find it funny I don't find
Indian Comedy funny that's that's my
taste okay that has nothing to do with
whether you like it or not but I had
never heard of Samina so this clip comes
out out on Sunday uh and there is R
there samay Rina and there are some four
other people there there's a lady called
apurva and there is a a guy called
Ashish chalani and there's a sick
gentleman uh and apparently this show
was behind a pay wall so you had to be a
paying member of this channel to access
the show so clearly a paying member of
this channel leaked this clip so in this
clip that's leaked I mean there's some
stuff that the lady says that's terribly
crash in objectionable and then there's
the two things that R says the first
thing he said was he jokingly offered a
person 2 CR rupees and he said but you
have to do this to me and something very
objectionable and secondly he uh did a
whatif question about a mom dad scenario
and that's what's really uh caused the
controversy and once this came out
there's been this Witch Hunt against him
this Lynch Mob online he has been
absolutely crucified and he has been
thrown under the bus by lots of people
who he hosted on his podcast which is
very nice to see and I saw this on
Monday this came out probably on Sunday
last Sunday and I probably saw this on
Monday today is Saturday right this
Monday I'm talking
about now what's my reaction to what I
saw I was appalled by what I saw okay
I'm saying very honestly was this clip
was what rir said horrible yes it was
horrible was it atrocious yes it was
atrocious he said what he said was it
disgusting it was disgusting was it
unacceptable yes unacceptable I am
extremely disappointed with what he said
and I am extremely sad that he has
landed himself in the
situation and when I saw this I was
wondering how did ranir Imagine such a
scenario with with Mom and Dad in it
about parents how do you imagine that I
am at my age I have never imagined that
that
scenario regarding your once's parents
right so how did he imagine that and I
was really surprised because I know rir
quite well I know he's not pervert rir
is not a pervert and he's not a cheap
sleazy person so how did he imagine this
sort of scenario and then more Clips
started coming out one video clip came
out from 2015 in which some some
comedian apparently called Kanan Gill
apparently he's a comedian so it's a
clip from 2015 in which Kanan Gill a
comedian asks this same question to a
couple of actors okay and then another
clip came out from a YouTube channel
called UJ crew in which a lady called
Sam or Sammy Walsh who's an Australian
comedian she asked the same question and
this video is from about late January 26
25 which is about a couple of weeks
before the controversy starts so it's
clear that the the question that R asked
he asked those people the the statements
he made the question the scenario Mom
and Dad thing it was clearly copied and
that was incredibly stupid right so uh
Ren made three mistakes essentially the
first thing that that he went to Sam
show which I believe I have come to hear
is has a reputation for vulgarity many
people would call it vulgar so first
mistake he went to Sam show second
mistake he made two horrible jokes and
thirdly one of those jokes involved
parents because see in India there are
tabos certain things are taboo you don't
speak about that first thing you don't
talk about religion you don't make jokes
about religion second you don't make
jokes about cast third you don't make
jokes about politics and fourth you
don't make jokes about parents in a way
that is disrespectful you don't do that
parents are supposed are regarded as God
in our culture isn't it so you don't do
these things these are taboos in India
and and ranir clearly broke the last
taboo he kind of made a
joke uh that involved parents and that
was disrespectful and it's really sad
that he didn't did not think before say
saying what he sad said now here's what
I think could have happened okay this is
an educated guest
guess
first he probably was invited to appear
on this show samina's show okay so once
this happens you do your due diligence
so ranir steam must have been must have
done their due diligence and looked at
sa Samina and they would have seen that
Rina is a highly respected person
because he was recently apparently
hosted by Shri amitab bachan G India's
most legendary actor samay Rina was
hosted by amitab bachan G so then the
team must have concluded that it should
be fine to go on uh Samaya show for anir
despite the vulgarity and that's why
they must have accepted the uh request
to appear on this show and then
obviously when you decide that you're
going on a show you need to be prepared
you need to do some homework so it's a
it's a comedy show it's a vulgar comedy
show so then Ran's team would have
researched what kind of jokes are
appropriate for a show of this this this
quality so they must have done some
research looked at other funny podcasts
or vulgar podcast or whatever and they
must have dug up these uh edgy or vulgar
jokes which are already online like the
thing that Kanan Gil and and Sam Walsh
said and the must have said that see
it's already online it's there for a
long time and even an Indian comedian
has made these jokes so it should be
fine so that's why they must have
decided that ranir will say these jokes
and they would have advised R to say
these jokes and probably ranir said okay
green light and that's why this whole
thing happened that's what I think
happened okay it's a speculation but
it's an educated guess now I understand
why everyone is angry especially the
ones who are considered to be on India
in India's right wing and I can assure
you that the left wing is Overjoyed with
what's happening right now the online
lynching of of ranir see I understand
why this why this anger is there ran is
seen as a role model for young
men yeah he seen as Big Brother b b
right that's what he is called he's seen
as a dharmic person he does meditation
he does sad all that and I sure that
ranir has consciously contributed to the
creation of this
perception so he is seen as a dharmic
person he is seen seen as a role model
as a big brother and then he goes and
cracks these horrible jokes so clearly
there's going to be a sense of betrayal
there's going to be a sense of this
person is a hypocrite right and the
Indian audience hates hypocrisy we are
perfectly fine with evil hateful
anti-national people who are well
behaved
we will watch passively as people
denigrate our culture and our religion
and our gods and our temples on TV
debates we will watch passively we'll
watch passively as people abuse our
nation on TV in on TV debates in the
name of free speech we'll watch
passively we will watch passively as
ringas are given free education at our
expense taxpayer expense and we are
perfectly fine while with our world
being slowly dismantled and destroyed as
long as it's done properly in a well-
behaved apparently civilized
manner but when a
person says stupid things and makes
these clearly disgusting jokes we're
going to crucify no forgiveness possible
right so runway's mistake was that he
thought he could compartmentalize
different aspects of his life he thought
he could separate his brand image which
comes from his podcast and his Vlogs
from his activities as a guest or other
podcasts and other shows and that's a
big mistake because you cannot do that
as a public figure you can't now let me
reiterate I dislike
vulgarity I dislike swearing cross
language I don't think it's funny I
don't think it's it's it's comedy this
sort of stuff okay and once again let me
reiterate that I that what ranir said
was was cross it was horrible it was
atrocious disgusting
unacceptable and to me extremely
disappointing so the question is what
should be done about ranir H is he a
disgusting creep who should be crucified
after all he made this horrible joke
about parents so let me ask you
something my dear
viewers have you seen Shri Virat kohi
score a
century yes have you seen Shri Rohit
Sharma score a century so you hit the
the
the runs you reach 100 watch Mr K's
first 20 centuries or so what is the
word or the words that he
utters after reaching this great
milestone and what about Mr Rohit Sharma
what are the words they like to utter in
times of emotional turmoil and when you
have achieved a
milestone there's two
words you know there's two words one is
an abuse that involves
sisters the other is an AB abuse that
involves
mothers and these two words that are so
common on the cricket field among giants
like Ki and roit Sharma these words
these two words are not jokes they are
downright
abuses so I would like to ask the people
who are hyperventilating about
ranir where was uh your outrage when
this was this has been happening common
commonly it's common place in the
cricket field what happened to your
outrage what happened to your family
values and how many of you my viewers
use these words all the
time I'm pretty certain many of you do
that you don't even think about what it
means you just go ahead this that right
so who's the hypocrite now yeah sure
ranvir is portrayed or maybe he portrays
himself as a dharmic person who does
meditation sadna and then he goes and
cracks bad jokes terrible horrible jokes
sure but aren't we if we also use such
language aren't we also
hypocritical H and we have to understand
the context in which all of this happens
there is a long-standing
tradition of of of of this this sort of
thing of
vulgarity all across media let's let's
talk about some let's talk about
Bollywood right have you heard the song
Ang
angana Bollywood song It's a song that
people play during holy
celebrations what is the the double
meaning the
duble in Ang it's the act of culation
isn't it such a terrible thing to talk
about on this show but that's what it is
it's the act of sexual intercourse that
is angas
and people dance to this song this this
disgusting vulgar song in holy it's
normal great actors do that right what
about Chul P what about DK B these are
great songs Everybody Plays them have
nice right and and these are just some
examples and there are many more such
Third Rate Bollywood songs and many of
these songs are played on high volume on
loudspeakers during navaratri
celebrations
and nobody bats an eyelid so who is the
hypocrite here is ranir a hypocrite or
are we all Hypocrites that we that we
don't to raise our voice against this
what about cheap movies in Bollywood
cool Grand musty yeah what about the
cheap BJ Puri songs with their babby
jokes you people don't have a problem
with that what happened to those
disgusting despicable Orchestra shows in
in Bihar but which is the epitome of
live
vulgarity right and then if you have a
problem with profanity and vulgarity
there is that online all over the place
the current 47th president of the United
States he has been known to use
profanity some of the words that vat
kohi would use but translated into
English he's been known to use that Elon
Musk swears all the time he does crash
stuff all the time on on X one of the
most beloved comedians in India Russell
Peters he uses profanity all the time
nobody bats an eyelid Joe Rogan uses
profanity all the time and then there is
pornography on
Twitter no issue we don't have an issue
with that right and there is actual soft
pornography on Instagram done by Indians
done by actual mother son
Duos yeah it's it's there on Instagram
but we have no issue with that and there
is V ity and this nudity on all of our
OT platforms crass stuff but we don't
have an issue with that and we have an
issue with with run who's the Hypocrites
here
H and do you know you think that
vulgarity is something that's coming
recently through because of Western
intervention in India do you think the
West has made India vulgar do you know
that do you think that our ancestors who
spoke Sanskrit 5,000 years ago they had
no profanity do you think
so there is a Russian
word it's called yat it's the Russian
equivalent of the English f word yat
it's also the same thing in Ukrainian
yat do you know what is the root word of
yat it is the Sanskrit verb
yti what does Yaba mean I will leave
that to you as an exercise as homework
and let me show you this
uh inscription okay let's let's do this
let me show you this inscription from
ad all
right
um uh so I'll just leave it there
briefly and remove it you can pause the
video later and watch it if you
like uh that is a clear uh example of
profanity uh 700 years ago 700 plus
years ago in
Sanskrit
so we Indians we hate hypocrisy but
often times we ourselves are hypocrit
hypocrites a majority of India's
population swears especially youngsters
everybody routinely uses the words that
kohi and and Rohit use that abuse
mothers and sisters we all know this but
we pretend like it doesn't exist and we
are all you
know we all holy or something and the
fact is that vulgarity exists in every
culture in every society a certain
percentage of your population is
perfectly comfortable with vulgarity and
because of this there is a demand for
vulgar content in entertainment and
where there is a demand there's going to
be people who will cater to that demand
they will serve that demand and that's
why we have vulgarity on OT platforms
and that's why we have the Samaya show
or India's Got latent show and that's
why people like rir stupidly make the
mistake of going on the show and then
behaving the way they've done so Samaya
and his show which apparently is vulgar
I've not Sur seen it but I'm told so
apparently s so Samaya and his show are
simply a symptom of the disease that is
prevalent in Indian Society in all
societies and R Ran's mistake stupid
mistake is a symptom of this disease
it's not the disease it's a symptom
Society a certain section certain
portion of society is rotten and how do
you address this rot how do we address
this
rot this can be addressed only by
reforming the education system it's
something I have been advocating forever
and your elected leaders don't care
about this we need an education system
that instills the right values and
behavioral traits but we won't have it
the education system will teach none of
that it won't teach you culture
civilization it'll just teach you
nothing it'll just waste your
time uh so
yeah so ranvir I know him personally
he's one of the nicest guys he's by no
means a pervert and if you look at it
unemotionally you will say that he has
genuinely Advanced the core the cause of
the so-called right-wing of India
greatly he has given his platform to so
to many right-wing authors and
personalities that nobody on the left
would ever have given a platform
to okay maybe he did it for views but so
what so what and I can also assure that
unlike I never take names do I I can
assure that unlike the brown or
the German Shepherd rir has never done
anything to harm the national interest
or to hurt the national
image he is not on any deep State
Payroll he's not an aspiring zalinski
he's not an anti-national the work
whatever work he has done has only
enhanced the national image mostly you
know so we in India have this uh what's
called the frog in the well syndrome or
the tall poppy syndrome when somebody
starts to do well and and do really well
for themselves we want to pull them down
we want to cut them to size so a lot of
people right now are jealous for a long
time they've been jealous of ranvir a
lot of people envy him in the recent his
success and those people are right now
gleefully celebrating his Misfortune and
a lot of people lot of creators lot of
influencers the past week have been
milking this controversy for views and
subscribers and whatnot and especially
the left Wingers are the happiest right
now so what should we do about ran huh
should we crucify R should we throw him
under the bus well I will not be
throwing him under the bus so let me
once again reiterate in case you have
missed it I do not find crassness funny
I do not enjoy vulgar comedy and the
words that he used on in that on that
show they were horrible they were crass
they were unex acceptable they're
indefensible and extremely disappointing
he made a stupid mistake a huge mistake
and he's paying for the mistake but I
don't think he deserves to be crucified
he deserves a second chance everybody
deserves a second chance once in their
life uh so that's my views on this can
ranvir come back well he will have to
atone for his mistake he will have to
pay the price for his mistake he's not a
kid he's grown up now so when you make a
big mistake today as a grownup you pay
the price for it unfortunately and he
he's going to have to genuinely
apologize again ask for for forgiveness
and then I think he can come back he
should come back what advice do I have
for
anir well who am I to give advice but if
I were to give advice first of all take
legal advice secondly fire your advisory
team fire them all apologize once again
ask for forgiveness genuinely from your
heart and take some time off and
reconnect with who you are where did you
go wrong and come back with
authenticity go International and if the
Witch Hunt continues leave the country
work from somewhere else that's what I
would say about uh
this controversy let's see what the live
chat is saying right
now
okay all right okay okay fine all right
get it so with that said I think that
that's the one Ty I'm going to speak
about this
okay now uh let's get into some more
questions a couple of questions related
to this matter so let's do it uh sorab
and it's me Aki what's what is freedom
of speech and freedom of expression in
the true sense and what are their
thresholds as a citizen of
India and uh people are reacting
violently to a joke very hypocritical
um is all is this the reason why the
main problems in India don't get
addressed
do you think freedom of speech is a myth
in India do you think we may never have
a show that PES the barrier
of Comedy limits set by inan people uh
what is freedom of speech it's the right
theoretic theoretical right to express
yourself and say exactly what you want
without censoring yourself in public
that's freedom of speech and freedom of
expression in the true sense what are
the
limits the thresholds of freedom of
speech in India I think the Constitution
and laws put some limits you cannot
offend you cannot say things against
religion you cannot say things against
certain eminent personalities whoever
they are I will not name them and other
things like that so there are legal
limitations on your freedom of speech
and then there are other restrictions on
V on freedom of speech so if you say
derogatory things against certain
religions you're going to have your head
chopped off in India and the law will do
nothing about it there is that so there
are multiple you know limitations and
and uh limitations and thresholds or
whatever you want to call it on
restrictions on free freedom of speech
you can only abuse Hinduism in India
that's perfectly fine uh but if you
abuse any other religion you're going to
be in deep deep
trouble so there is that and look so it
it doesn't mean that India is Baron the
US let's say or or the or Europe is
better
EU you know in in the EU they ARR
arresting people for for social media
posts right now it is like going back to
the days of fascism or or 1984 the book
The Novel you
know and uh in the US during Biden's
time you could be banned from Twitter
and all social media for having the
wrong opinions about politics and the
Corona virus and all that you would have
seen my older old older asab live
streams wherever I have mentioned the
word covid or Corona virus they put a
big disclaimer below the video and so on
so there are limitations on freedom of
speech
everywhere and at the end of the day
even if a nation theoretically gives you
complete freedom of speech there is no
free speech without consequences you may
be allowed to say whatever you want but
it doesn't mean there will be no
consequences so such is the way things
are in the world um why do lots of
problems in India do not get addressed
is it because of lack of freedom of
speech no it's because of other systemic
issues which we can discuss at a
different uh in a different
way okay dungar Singh Chan says what are
your thoughts on so-called dark humor
what is dark humor do you think that
should be a limit on what can be joked
about dark humor is a when you when you
when you joke about things that are
typically uh uh dark topics you know
death and depression and things like
that you know and uh it's it's it's an
art form uh dark humor is is an art form
not everybody can do it most people mess
it up very badly very badly uh let me
give you an example of what dark humor
is have you heard of James Franco James
Franco let me put James Franco's the
famous thing on the
screen so this I'm sure everybody's seen
that right this little meme thing the
guy is standing on a Gallows with the
nose around his neck he's about to be
hanged and he's smiling at the guy next
to him and asking is it the is it your
first time so that's dark humor okay
that's an example of dark humor dark
humor is also called Gallows humor so
it's it's something similar let me put
something
else
um so look this is an example of Gallow
humor okay and I better not the next
song is about see I mean this is
bordering on what many people would
would call vulgarity once again if you
can see what this is so I will not delve
deep into this otherwise somebody will
create an issue with me also so that
that's dark humor you know humor about
things that are that many people would
not find funny humor about dark topics
topics that are uncomfortable to many
people and only some people who have
gone through that can probably
understand that that's dark humor should
there be a limit to what can be joked
about
uh what do I think should there be a I
think certain things probably it depends
on the on the cultural and social
context in some Nations you can't joke
about certain things in some cultures
you can't joke about C certain things
it's just a cultural thing uh
theoretically well the world isn't
theoretical the world is a real world
thing in the real world there are
complications so I think there probably
should be some
limitations on on humor on freedom of
expression depending on the cultural
context of where you are in
Indonesia you can joke about certain
things and maybe not about certain
things in Saudi Arabia you can joke
about certain things probably not about
certain things in uh in China you can
can joke about certain things probably
not about certain things in um Itali you
probably can joke about certain things
not about the certain things not at all
yes in Germany you cannot joke about
certain things and same for India I
think it's it's more complex than people
make it make it seem people make
everything look like black and white
it's not black and white The World Isn't
black and white so I think there
probably should be some limitations and
every country and every culture can
decide what its limitations are and what
things are
taboo okay now that we dealt with that
let's talk about what's happening in the
world is big world out there lots of
things are happening lots of things
happening very fast so PR Paul has two
questions what do you make of Trump's
remarks post Putin talks and could India
have a role to play in the emerging
scenario Trump's called with Putin
followed by JD Van's meeting raises big
questions among certain European leaders
and Ukraine citizens are we witnessing
the end game for the Ukraine war with
negotiations seemingly bypassing
Ukraine's leadership is zelinsky's po
political script over European leaders
appear unsettled what does this shift
signal for NATO the EU and for Global
power dynamics is the US now openly
dictating the terms of the UK of
Ukraine's fate without even seeking
their
permission um okay what's what's going
on yeah so those of you who have been
following this show the askab show and
this channel since the Ukraine War began
will will know exactly what I have been
saying consistently throughout a lot of
questions have been raised by viewers
and rightfully so based on the media
reports Russia is losing Russia is
losing Ukraine is making great gains
Russia has lost half a million soldiers
Russia has lost all its military
supplies Putin has cancer Putin is dying
in three months all kinds of rumors have
been spread and I have been saying one
thing consistently
Russia is winning the war Russia will
prevail and Russia will achieve its
objectives and and now after what we
have seen the past week it is clear that
the end game is now
being operationalized the end game of
the Ukraine war the war is
ending and Trump and Putin have agreed
over a lengthy phone call to the broad
modalities of this end game but they
will then negotiate their minions will
negotiate the
details the Ukraine war is ending it's
end it's going to end exactly as I have
been saying since February 2022 with a
Russian Victory what are the modalities
that I just said first of all Russia
will keep all of its territorial gains
they took Crimea in 2014 they took
luhans donet and other places other
regions after 2022 and whatever other
gains they have made all the Russian
speaking regions and whatever other
territorial Gams have made those will
remain with Russia the pre 2022
boundaries of Ukraine are now a thing of
the past Ukraine is going to be
partitioned so Russia gets it keeps his
territorial games that's number one
secondly the US has agreed essentially
to renounce NATO membership for Ukraine
Ukraine will never become a member of
NATO third the US has agreed there will
be no further US military aid to Ukraine
fourth there's going to be no US troops
in Ukraine fifth it's the EU not the US
that will guarantee Ukraine's uh
security whatever that means okay um and
for the US there's a nice Face Saver
what's the Face Saver Ukraine will
provide the US with about $500 billion
doar worth of minerals and rare Earths
and whatnot so the US gets its
investment back Ukraine loses territory
uh Russia achieves everything it wanted
to achieve demilitarization and
denazification of Ukraine done
denazification done demilitarization
they'll they'll ensure it's done okay so
it's it's essentially a win for Russia
they get everything they want and the US
gets a nice Face Saver which looks like
a win-win because they get half trillion
dollars of minerals in rare Earths from
Ukraine Ukraine has Lo lost the flower
of its demography all the young men are
gone um the economy is
devastated and now what happens what is
next next there's going to be regime
change in Kiev a neutral regime will be
placed in Kiev right now who's the who's
leading in Kiev Mr zelinsky Mr zelinsky
is is the leader of Ukraine so if Mr
zelinski is lucky he will be allowed to
relocate to the us somewhere maybe in
the U EU us wherever and enjoy whatever
billions of dollars he has he has
acquired as a consequence of this
terrible terrible War if he's lucky
generally people aren't that lucky so we
will see about that so this is a win for
Russia and it's also a Face Saver for
the US um the Europeans the EU is
insignificant the US isn't Consulting
the EU the US isn't going to take
permission from the EU leaders about
what happens now Trump is going to tell
them this is what happens and the EU has
to swallow that whol sale and there's no
question of Consulting with ziny or the
Ukrainian leadership who are nothing but
puppets of the
US the US like you say prai is clearly
openly dictating the terms of Ukraine's
fate and also Europe's
fate there's no question of seeking
permission why would Europe Overlord
seek your permission why would that
happen uh so it's the end game is being
now the end game phase is now
starting um negotiations will be tough
they'll try and bargain and and get as
much out of it both sides the Americans
in Russia does India have a role to play
it depends if if uh Putin so wants he
may have India come in uh India
obviously as we know is a nice nation
good boy we are a good boy we we are
friends with everybody uh the West likes
us the Russians like us the Russians
trust us and so on so if required they
can bring India in but most probably
they will not need India but if India is
required then we will obviously be happy
to give to offer our services so it is
the end of the Ukraine war the beginning
of the end of the Ukraine war exactly as
I've been saying for the past three
years everybody has been laughing and
Bing blah blah blah well here we are
today exactly as I said and it's it's
you know I'm not trying to be gleeful
and and rejoice or anything it is a
humanitarian disaster it was completely
avoidable a beautiful nation and so many
innocent people and what's happened is
is a crime and zalinski zeleni will go
down in history as as as a quisling as a
traitor a man who betrayed his nation
and his people a man who colluded with a
foreign power to destroy his
Nation that's what he will be
remembering in history
for H I have nothing but contempt for
for someone like him and I assure you
there are many aspiring zalinskis in
bhat okay I will I will not name anybody
but I'm sure you can think of a few
yourselves vasu
sing says this is the first time I'm I'm
posting a question well you got lucky
must have been a good question let's see
what it is the recent visit of PM Modi
to the US did not feel very energetic
okay it was another lame right that's
quite a word the chemistry between Mr
Modi and Trump which is overhyped in the
media didn't look the way it used to
look in the past something has changed
this is a very different Trump we're
dealing with I think is going to be very
tough on India this time more than last
time to say the least he might persuade
us which is a nice word to buy f35s to
make him happy what do you think about
it well you're right this is not the
same Trump trump 45 during his first
term as president was an isolated man he
had no backers he had no friends his own
party was conspiring against him the
Democrats hated him the media hated him
the world leaders hated him he had no
friends nobody liked
him Mr Modi was good to him Mr Modi
treated him as as with warmth and
friendship and Mr Trump really
appreciated that and he was grateful to
Mr Modi for being nice to him okay
despite be in India not being an equal
of the US in any way whatsoever Mr Trump
was very grateful and the two men
clearly forged some sort of bond a bond
of friendship right so that's why during
their dealings and interactions
during Mr Trump's previous tenure
president the 45th president the
relationship and the body
language was very different at the time
Mr Trump was grateful to Mr Modi he was
grateful for Mr modi's friendship and
for the warm hospitality and welcome
that he got and so on very few world
leaders gave that to him very few of his
own political allies in in the US did
that to him his own party people were
hostile against him so there was a very
different Mr Trump that time and he had
the entire array might of the deep State
arrayed against him that's Trump
45 today we are talking about Trump 47
this is a different Beast alog together
he has the entire might of the deep
State behind him not against
him and this time he is on a mission
this time everything is with him the
entire might of the American political
system is on his side the entire
technological might of the US AI might
space might everything on is on his side
this is a man Unleashed and Mr Trump is
on a mission to be the biggest B baddest
greatest president of the US since
George Washington surpassing Abraham
Lincoln that's the mission he is
on and when you're in that mental
mode when you deal with the leader of a
of a nation that is not even one tenth
of your power the dynamic is going to be
very different it's just going to be
visible that it it's well you know you
know I'm Indian right but just to be
completely
honest it's it's
like a mouse dealing with an
elephant the relationship is like that
okay we we have to be honest with
ourselves we can't delude ourselves oh
we are visha Guru we are superpower in
five years s what the hell be realistic
so that's the thing now Trump still
likes
Modi Trump he's probably Trump's
favorite leader on a personal level but
personal relationships count for nothing
in geopolitics you may be the best of
friends but when you are the leaders of
two countries and you're negotiating you
negotiate with your full might and when
the US negotiates with its full might
well there's nothing India can do about
it but say yes
sir uh so
um I don't think that uh the recent
visit was lame there were many positives
and all um of course Mr Trump decided
certain things apparently on our behalf
that yeah India is buying F35 are you
sure Mr Trump that sort of thing but
it's a different Trump we're dealing
with he is an absolute Beast this time
he is going to be tough on India for
sure he's going to get India to do
everything he wants India to
do but I don't think he is going to be
unnecessarily unfair on
India because of his relationship with
Mr Modi he may actually be a little bit
lenient towards India uh so yeah that's
that's how I see it it isn't all
bad okay dark whatever dark LW something
says so finally reciprocal tariffs are
imposed by Donald Trump how is this
decision beneficial for the US it can
cause trade Wars and is there any
solution our prime minister has to
tackle this is India going to suffer
because of this tariff game see tariffs
are trade barriers you have let's say
Nation X exporting a product y to the US
X nation is exporting product wi let's
say it's a mouse let's say it's a mouse
okay and let's say the mouse costs for
the sake of argument
$100 uh now when the US exports things
to this nation let's say this nation
imposes 30% tariffs so if something cost
100 bucks they're going to sell for 130
bucks in that Nation right so what the
US will do is it's going to look at
every nation scan whatever the practices
are and the US is now going to impose
reciprocal tariffs on every nation maybe
the tariffs will be equal to what these
nations impose in the US or maybe
they'll be double or maybe whatever they
want and when the US imposes tariffs it
it makes other nations crumble because
then where do you export to the US is
the biggest market and the US can choke
your economy and so on so that's why
it's a great tool of Leverage against
Nations okay let's say France is EXP
reporting champagne and red wine to the
US and let's say one bottle of champagne
costs 100 bucks $100 and let's say Trump
is displeased with M Emanuel mro so he
says I impose a 100% tariff on you sir
so now that bottle of red wine which was
costing $100 will now cost $200 in the
US so who will buy it nobody will buy it
and then the French will have no place
to sell this red wine too because the
biggest Market is the US now what do
they do with the Surplus Red Line red
wine do they let it uh stagnate what do
they do it's a big problem right so
that's called Leverage that's how you
get somebody on the negotiating table
and get them to do whatever you want
it's a form of arm twisting do you see
that now obviously he has so he has
Trump has imposed these reciprocal
tariffs on
everybody All Nations not just us okay
so it's not something against us um now
when it comes to us
India we have some tariffs on American
Products
but for about
75% of the stuff that we import from the
US we impose 5% or less
tariff so that's essentially a
nonissue it's just some things that that
can be negotiated about so I don't think
it's going to be a big problem for India
and I don't think that Mr Modi is going
to uh do anything that displeases Mr
Trump we're going to talk we're going to
have our officials with with their
officials we're going to have discussion
we're going to look at things one by one
case by case product by Product Industry
by industry sector by sector and we're
going to come at what the whatever the
best kind of arrangement or agreement is
I don't think it's going to be a bone of
contention between India and the US I
think we're going to negotiate and
resolve this very amicably it's not
going to be a problem India is not going
to suffer I assure you of
that okay next question is by three
people sakam narvar Anonymous scientist
and prar Gupta what is India getting out
of this recent Trump Modi talks it all
looks like one-sided bullying okay
you're talking about the trade and
tariffs right uh what are your views on
the recently concluded Modi Trump and
Modi musk meeting what conclusions can
we make from this meeting what are views
and key takeaways of Mr Mod's meeting
with m m and US ministers like Vance
Trump Vance gabard toy gabard Elon Musk
and eventually Mr
Trump okay so listen um uh
um I don't think it's all one-sided
bullying of course he it's interesting
that Mr Trump announced those reciprocal
uh tariffs against the whole world just
before his meeting with Mr Modi so it
was a good it was a classic Trump move
the art of the deal where's the book
somewhere around here the art of the
deal good
book so yeah that that makes it sound
like one-sided bullying but it's a great
negotiating tactic okay uh
um
now uh I will not deal with Mr modi's
dealing with meeting with Mr M here but
he met with uh Vice President Van very
nice meeting Mr van is has a Indian
family right his wife has Indian kids
are half Indian so that's a nice
connection to have and Mr Modi gave some
gifts to Mr Vance's
kids um Mr Modi met again with Miss Tuli
gabard uh they know each other for for
more than a decade uh miss gabard the
first time she came to India or for the
first time Mr Modi went there I think
Tuli gabard presented Mr Modi with her
personal copy of the bhagwat Gita she's
a she's a Hindu vnav so they have a
long-standing u friendship with each
other let's say and very warm
relationship so they met again and miss
miss Tuli gabard is now the director of
the National Intelligence Agency so she
is the boss of all the intelligence
agencies in the US she's been confirmed
very powerful position
so it was nice to meet her I'm sure for
Mr Modi he met with Mr Elon Musk who
came with his kids which is kind of a
power move to bring your kids to a big
meeting that sort of thing and I'm not
sure what transpired in that I'm sure
Elon Musk wants India to allow Starling
to beam into every home I'm not sure
what the situation is there on that and
I'm sure Mr Modi must have must have
urged Elon Musk to you know launch Tesla
in India and those Giga factors and all
that I'm not sure what transpired but it
it was a reasonably friendly and warm
meeting and Elon Musk is obviously a
very powerful man today and then Mr Modi
met with Mr Trump now this was a good
bilateral meeting many positives came
out of it no real negatives right so uh
one of the things that uh that that were
discussed uh so first of all the good
thing for a change is that there was
absolutely no talk of Human Rights and
minority rights and all that nonsense
the Biden Administration used to do that
every time I remember the first time Mr
Modi went to the US after the B after
the Biden Administration came in and he
had this uh press conference of some
press meet with uh Kamala Harris and
Miss Harris lectured Mr Modi about human
rights and all that in front of the
press yeah so this time there was no
talk of Human Rights and minority rights
no lecturing right the two Nations have
agreed to uh double bilateral trade more
than double bilateral trade right now
bilateral trade is about 1 $30 billion a
year so by 2030 the Nations have
resolved both Nations have resolved that
we will uh expand or bilateral trade
augment it to about $500 billion half a
trillion dollars so that's the objective
and we're going to work towards that so
that's a very positive uh Outlook uh
obviously they've discussed addressing
trade imbalances uh uh India will now
procure more more oil and gas from the
US yeah uh there is a talk of Defense
corpor and
purchases uh we purchasing the striker
thing and some of stuff there a new
10year framework for uh for what we call
the major defense partnership uh between
the two Nations we're going to deepen
other security cooperation in the Indo
Pacific region which is a wield
reference to China and India has a sure
the US will take back whatever illegal
immigrants are there we will take them
back no issues we will not cause any
problems
um and Mr Trump has claimed that India
India will be uh purchasing the F35 well
that that that remains to be seen that
remains to be seen um so that's the deal
right now okay so I think it was a very
positive meeting um and I see the this
this visit of Mr Modi to the US it was
essentially a reconnection with Mr Trump
it's about reconnecting uh reviewing
where we stand today and agreeing on on
what needs to be done and then the two
Nations will get to work this is just
the
beginning and I think the next four
years India us relations could could
reach the Pinnacle the greatest they
have ever been Mr Modi and Mr Trump
imagine them dancing hand in hand that
sort of thing Could Happen uh how good
it will be for India we have to see but
the relations could be really good uh
the next four years or
so okay this had to be asked mclen
Ashish Ashish
karish and PR Paul some journalist asked
Donald Trump about the Deep State and
Soros Junior's involvement in Bangladesh
Trump said I leave Bangladesh to PM Modi
what are My Views about this when Trump
was asked about Bangladesh he said a
very curious thing he said India has
been handling them for hundreds of years
Bangladesh is barely half a century old
what are the implications of that quot
and PR says when asked about us deep
State involvement in Bangladesh's regime
change efforts Trump deflected saying I
will leave Bangladesh Mr Modi is this
just diplomatic rhetoric or does it
signal a potential shift in US strategy
will the US truly step back or is this a
deeper geopolitical Ploy what should
India's next steps be in navigating the
situation so yesterday I was on the 900m
debate on Republic TV with arnab Arab go
Swami and Arab is of the opinion that
Trump has left Bangladesh to
India that's it I'm handing it over to
you you do what you want that's what is
the that's what his understanding was
and I completely disagree with that this
was when Trump was asked this question
about
Bangladesh we all know that this was a
US regime change operation the ouer of
shikina and the bringing in of this
puppet Muhammad
yunus that's a US deep State operation
and it's an operation I predicted nine
months before it
happened so um it's clear it's a it's a
deep change deep State regime change
operation done by the US and when Trump
was asked about this and about soros's
involvement and all that
Trump deflected the question he did not
want to answer it that's why he made the
cryptic remark I leave Bangladesh to PM
Modi it doesn't mean that he is handing
over Bangladesh to India and you can get
rid of Muhammad yunus and bring back she
kazina absolutely not he simply did not
want to answer the question so he made
this remark that can be interpreted in
00 different ways that I leave
Bangladesh to Mr Modi he essentially was
saying that Mr Modi can take this
question I will not take
it okay now what is the deal with
Bangladesh is Trump going to reverse the
regime change operation in Bangladesh is
he going to bring shik back what about
that we have to understand this using
the the Dynamics of Leverage and
geopolitical power equations okay see
Trump is concerned about two Nations
justifiably concerned about the two
nearest peer Rivals of the US Russia and
China Russia is a military near
superpower China is an economic near
superpower okay so Trump is justifiably
concerned about these two Nations his
big
rivals and he's going to focus most of
his energy on his engagement and his
dealings with these two Powers now what
gives him leverage over Russia and what
gives him leverage over
China the two things that give Trump
leverage over
Russia are having Europe under
control and having India under
control right now Trump owns the US owns
the EU and NATO so all the European
nations essentially are non Sovereign
Nations who are owned by the US so it is
completely under Us control they can't
do a thing against him
India is a Sovereign Nation so Trump
needs leverage against India so if he
has leverage over the EU and India it
gives Trump leverage over Russia because
Russia has very few friends India is one
of the few friends Russia has when it
comes to China China wants to deal with
Europe China wants to export to the EU
market and the US market there is a
trade war going on so China can't now
export profitably to the US and EU will
do the same thing so they can't even
export to to the EU so China now needs
to export to India that's why they
trying to be friends with us now for the
past year or so past few months but if
India is under control by the us or of
India or if India is on the American
side then that also becomes a huge
problem for China China gets
isolated so it is very important for
Trump to have leverage over India what
is
leverage Leverage is pressure points and
pain points different ways of applying
pain if required so what leverage does
Mr Trump have against India let's go to
the map we haven't opened the map today
where's the map let's bring the map in
where is the map here is map yes so
here's the map now the geography will
show us the leverage points that Mr
Trump has Visa V India the first
leverage obviously that he has is
reciprocal tariffs which which we
discussed the other leverages are the
first Leverage is
Pakistan West Pakistan which is a us
vasal the word I have popularized
globally Pakistan West Pakistan is a us
wasal so that's a pressure point a
leverage Point against India they can
leverage it anytime against India to put
pressure on India another pressure point
or leverage point is Bangladesh East
Pakistan they own it now they own the
government they have done the regime
change why will they give it up third
the Americans of Afghanistan
the Taliban receives a stipend a weekly
stipend in cash from the US from between
40 to100 million a week so Taliban is a
us wasal why would they give it up right
then there is Bhutan now starlink has
been operationalized in Bhutan so that
can be used as a pressure point against
India as leverage against India then
there is the whole situation in Burma
which is spilled over into Manipur and
being a complete disaster it is not a
low and Order situation in Manipur it is
a geopolitical situation just like
Kashmir in the '90s was was not an
internal Law and Order Miss issue it was
terrorism coming from Pakistan it was a
geopolitical matter similarly what's
happening in Manipur is the same thing
so all of this is being done by the US
Manipur the
disaster is a deep state for creation
okay and these are some of the pressure
points leverage points they have against
India then there are certain allegedly
some political parties Within India that
the US allegedly has influence or
control over allegedly that's leverage
there are many aspiring zalinskis in
India you know I think we know that then
there are all these Christian Missionary
organizations in India these are
leverage points there are noos there are
activists there are journalists there
are professors and academics all these
are different kinds of Leverage
leverages that us has over India right
so my question is if you have all
these all this
leverage that that can help you
pressurize India so that India will do
what you want why would you give it
up why would you give it up so do you
think really that Trump will give up
whatever theyve achieved in Bangladesh
he has gone off the deep State he has
dismantled us Aid sure but he has gone
after the after the Deep state which
affected him he has not said thing
against the Deep States operations
outside of the US he dismantled the the
U us Aid right does it mean that money
can no longer flow into Bangladesh or
Pakistan or to various zalinskis in
India do you think so what is the
National Endowment for democracy what is
Freedom House H what is the national
Democratic Institute what is the Ford
what is Ford Foundation what's the rock
filler Foundation what is open Society
founded by George Soros what is the
maatha foundation what The Gates
Foundation what's oam which is a UK
based organization I can give you a 100
more names like
these all these organizations do exactly
what USA was
doing so they have only shut down USA
because they USA was interfering against
Trump was acting against Trump and
funding various media outlets and all
that which were anti-trump and anti-
Republicans so that's why they've shut
that that down but they are not shutting
anything else
down so
the long and the short of my answer is
that the US will not give up its
Leverage The Leverage they've built in
Bangladesh by carrying out a regime
change operation absolutely
not so uh whoever thinks whoever
believes whoever imagines that Trump is
leaving Bangladesh to India is gravely
mistaken he just did not want to answer
the question that's what that's all it
was vickram geopolitical says I found it
extremely hilarious how Trump uh blamed
uh the accent of Indian and Afghan
reporters when asked about khalistani
separatism and Afghan issues he easily
understood other questions from Indian
journalists which he liked during the
press conference well Trump is a very
intelligent man he's a very shrewd uh
person uh if he doesn't want to answer
some questions he will find the right
pretext so clearly he could understand
the questions asked by lots of Indian
reporters who all have the same accent
but someone asks about khalistan he
doesn't want to answer that so he I I
don't understand a word of what you're
saying and an Afghan person of the afans
have similar accent as Indians being
subcontinental so yeah he he deflected a
question from an Afghan reporter as well
so yeah don't answer inconvenient
questions one thing you will understand
if you deal with powerful people
politicians
Etc um and and public figures is if you
want them to answer your question don't
ask very tough questions they have they
are under no obligation to to answer
your question they'll find an excuse not
to answer it so look what does it mean
for us the khalistan issue right we know
the Americans have been harboring
khalistani terrorists and separatists on
their soil and they have been supporting
the similar harboring of khalistani
terrorist and separatists on Canadian
soil on UK soil in Australian soil New
Zealand five eyes
Nations they all the all these nations
do what the Americans tell them to do
because the Americans are the boss
and look uh Trump once again it's it's
it's leverage they have against India
they will not want to dismantle that
leverage they have over India so it's
inconvenient it's not nice to do that
but you need that so you don't answer
the question you deflect it you sidestep
sidestep it and you brush it under the
carpet and that's what Mr Trump
did
right is good question this one
importantance so Arian on the bomb Shan
97 and nand kizor 1233 what do you make
of the PM's prime minister modi's us
visit we already covered that f35s are
offered to India should we take it they
seem to be better than Su 57 Suk 57s
what's better Suk 57 or F35 and what's
better for India I heard that if we go
for the F35 us wasn't want doesn't want
to share the source code so we will have
trouble in mounting the brahos and other
Indian missiles to it because we have a
lot of missiles of our own obviously we
don't want something like that like our
if officers will
uh uh will sit in the
F35 and the F35 will be like kindly
provide OTP from us to start
the get an OTP from the US and then we
will start the engine it's quite a way
of putting it across and Trump is
putting pressure on India to buy the F35
the Russians two days back give a deal
we cannot refuse yes full technology
transfer Manufacturing in India where
the suco 30 was manufactured no extra
cost of setting up plants indianized mki
version of the Su 57 Hypersonic missile
of so 57 with full thick transfer and
Manufacturing in India it could be a big
blender if you let this offer slip away
what's your thoughts can we consider
ourselves a vasal if we buy the F35
rejecting this great
deal good questions excellent questions
good
points how good is this is the is the
F35 it's not a very fast plane it's it's
a stealthy plane for sure okay it's a it
can be detected through certain Radars
but you can't really pinpoint where it
is and The Radars that can pinpoint
locations can't find it so it's a good
stealy aircraft it's not particularly
fast a it's hardly
Supersonic and when you mount missiles
on it its stealth disappears because
those missiles don't have stealth
features so if you put the brahos on the
Su on the F35 by by stealth if you put
other asra or whatever the hell else
stealth gone that's a problem now the
same obviously applies of the soai 57 as
well right
so that's a draw one one right over
there the thing with the
F35 is that first of all it comes with a
kill
switch a kill switch let me tell the
story again in the 1980s the Australians
bought F f-15s from the Americans I
think think it was F15 the Australians
bought from the Americans and when the
Australians then took the plane for a
ride for a fly for the spin and they
tried to test out the various uh weapon
systems they found the Australians that
the planes the Americans had sold them
would not lock onto targets the
Australians wanted to lock onto it
refused so the planes targeting system
would only lock on to targets that were
pre-approved by the Americans that was a
big issue and then there was software
that the Americans would not allow the
Australians to maintain so it was a huge
issue the Australians were finally able
to crack this only in the 2000s or
2010s how many decades did the waste
like this with a useless
plane now the Americans if they give us
the F35 there's going to be all kinds of
such issues they can 100% they'll be
able to remotely disable the plane if
they feel like it the software will not
be able to maintain it it is extremely
expensive to maintain This Plane it's
extremely expensive to flight flight you
know how much it costs per hour of
flight very expensive spare parts are
expensive they can shut down spare parts
if they like they can shut down spares
if they like all kinds of issues right
now we have the Tes fighter plane which
is stalled because the Americans are not
supplying us with the engines right we
already see what dependency on the US
does to us now you want to buy a whole
aircraft and that to the price point is
ridiculous more than a $100 million per
piece I mean what what you doing bro so
uh and then you have to also sign all
kinds of agreements that open up your
spectrum your Airwaves to the Americans
and there'll be inspecting it on a
regular basis all kinds of intrusive
things you have to agree to when it
comes to the F35 when it comes to Su 57
absolutely
nothing so I'm not sure on balance which
is the better aircraft but with the Suk
57 we know the Russians won't remotely
disable it they won't block any spares
they w't force you to sign all kinds of
intrusive uh agreements that that allow
them to essentially penetrate your your
security and defense installations none
of that we know the Russian track record
we know how they have been with us for
decades at least that much we can trust
we know because we have been dealing
with them since the since the 20th
century so I think if the Russians are
offering that they will have India set
up production lines of the Suk 57 in
India and let's say they offer full
technology transfer then we should set
it up over here and we should crank out
couple of hundred of these or 300 of
these or whatever is good number in the
wisdom of the army and their and and and
its leadership Air Force and its
leadership let them
decide so that way we'll have full
control of of the
system and uh technology transfer will
is obviously very welcome especially if
you get the jet engine Tech transfer as
well obviously it'll cost money pay the
money please pay the money and get it
you get the tech so I would say if you
consider all of these factors it's a
no-brainer we should go for the suoy
57 Trump obviously wants us to buy it
the
F35 well you you can't you can't force
us to buy that it's not a good deal for
us it's it's actually terrible deal for
us uh so we have to Plate him by buying
something else or whatever we'll buy
some maybe more chuks or more Apaches or
or or or or more posidon aircraft or
whatever but we we should not buy the
F35 please good God please don't do that
all
right saaj and McLovin say why did
starlink start operating in Bhutan
Bhutan is a small poor sparsely
populated country but some kind of talks
are going on between India and Bhutan
the area is highly sensitive for India
what implications does starlink what
implications will starink have on Bhutan
and India what are the object of
starlink for the US starlink has been
launched in Bhutan right between India
and Chinese occupied Tibet uh by now we
have understood that our government
priorities um punishing communes on
National
Security but why isn't China doing
anything about this do they have some
technology that interferes with the the
starlink
network map map map map we need to uh
unleash the map to understand this
matter
let's have the map on the screen yes and
we zoom in and we're talking about this
small nation over here Bhutan very
important for us we have excellent
relations with
Bhutan uh Bhutan is our protectorate we
are responsible for the uh security and
territorial Integrity of Bhutan okay it
is our responsibility we have agreed to
this so Bhutan is our responsibility
it's our protectorate it is under our
protection and now
this past week when all this was going
on Elon Musk tweeted that starlink is
now operational in Bhutan so that is
what has happened so look at the
geographical location in it's between
India and Tibet uh between uh the
northern the Far Eastern part of India
Assam and and Tibet that's where Bhutan
is okay now we understand the geography
let's come here so what does starlink
mean for the us and what does starlink
what how does starlink contribute to uh
us geopolitical uh objectives right
that's the question starlink is
constellation of satellites in low earth
orbit they cover large parts of the
Earth's surface at any given point in
time and the beam the beam uh broadband
internet reasonably low low low latency
broadband internet to various parts of
the world uh musk says that starlink
beams are Switched Off over India
okay there's no way of knowing if he's
telling the truth or lying but
okay and I can assure
you I guarantee
this these Starling
satellites the thousands of these
satellites that are in orbit around the
Earth these satellites will also have
surveillance capabilities realtime
surveillance
capabilities I'm sure they have cameras
and other equipment instruments that
lead our whatever that can give you give
the US real time 24x7 surveillance of
any country they
want in high
resolution so maybe if I'm holding a
phone they'll be able to if I'm out
there wherever they'll be able to see
that this guy is holding a phone if I
have this time visible on the phone
then even that may be visible who knows
that that's how good it may be it's
definitely going to have surveillance
capabilities they'll be able to surveil
individuals if they want to in real time
so Starling is very important for the
US and uh why have they operationalized
it or Bhutan well one reason could be
that they want to interfere with India's
ability to to uh protect Bhutan and
maybe they have some Assets in Bhutan
you know local zalinskis and if
something happens they want to give uh
you know um reliable internet coverage
to those Zin that's one possible
explanation another explanation is that
maybe India and the US are working
together that's another explanation we
can we can consider we are doing a
theoretical exercise here so maybe India
and the US are working together and the
Chinese we know have territorial
aspirations over every nation and they
want to bite at pieces of bhutanese
territory as well Chinese so maybe it is
to counter the Chinese that this has
happened and maybe it's to counter India
as well as is
China so there are various possibilities
at play over here one of the
possibilities definitely is that U they
want to have starlink
operational in India's periphery in
India's areas of Interest we know
starlink is probably operational or or
or or Burma Myanmar maybe they claim
it's not but I'm sure it is and so on um
so yeah Starling is is an issue for us
Starling is definitely a threat to any
nation's sovereignty and just because
the man claims that staring is not being
beamed into India well I'm sure the
government of India has the means of
verifying this that whether he is
telling the truth or not but we have to
be really careful about this and why
isn't China doing anything about this
well what can the Chinese do about it
right what can they do will they start
shooting down
satellites that's an act of war and
that's going to cause space debris all
over the place which which is which will
be disastrous even for the Chinese and
their satellites so it's not an option
and they haven't even launched an
official protest because they don't own
Bhutan first of all uh so the Chinese
are also verily waiting and
watching vikra 97 says will these coming
four years be the biggest test of our
diplomacy PM Modi and Trump have
finalized deals in which India purchases
F35 fighter
jets automobiles oil and gas in the US
while it's good to have different
options and countries providing us with
essential Goods uh how will we uh be
able to manage relations with Russia and
China it will be difficult to purchase
military goods as well as energy from
both us and Russia simultaneously the
next four years are are going to be very
interesting and they're going to be
pretty difficult for India uh it is not
true that uh we have finalized a deal
for purchasing F35 fighter jets uh our
foreign Ministry has put out a
categorical statement that this is just
a suggestion that Mr Trump has made we
have not agreed to any such thing and we
will discuss this possibly in the future
uh automobiles we may be buying from
them sure oil and gas we're definitely
going to be buying from them just to
make them happy and not make them angry
is actually and so so it's good to have
options
yes um it's going to be a the cliche is
the tight rope walking act right that
we're going to try and balance out the
relations we want to be we don't want to
make the Americans unhappy we don't want
to make them angry but we also want to
safeguard our excellent relations with
Russia and the upcoming Ukraine
war end game is going to give
us a good opportunity to it's it's going
to be good in the sense that the US and
Russia once this happen happens won't
really be adversaries or or en Nations
there will definitely be
adversaries geopolitical adversaries but
there won't be enemies fighting a war
either directly or by proxy so once the
Ukraine war ends on whatever terms the
two Nations negotiate then then Mr Trump
and Mr Putin probably will regard each
other not as enemies anymore kind of
friends so they have decided that they
will visit each other's Nations so once
that happens you know tensions calm down
and once that happens for us it's good
so we can now say look we are dealing
with Russia but Russia is not your enemy
you're on good terms with Russia so you
know it should not be a problem for you
so it's going to give us uh more
breathing
space uh it's so uh what about China I
think with China it's going to be
difficult the Chinese have made over
churs to to us the past few months they
uh you know uh the troops which were in
advanced positions across the UN
demarcated Lac have been withdrawn the
state of high alert has gone down and U
whatever territorial uh gains the
Chinese may have done have been ruled
back and both both sides have going back
to the previous post 20 pre-2020 or
whatever patrolling routes and all that
so there have been efforts to to diffuse
the situation and the efforts have
worked uh Mr Modi and Mr Shi Jinping
also met in one of the the recent uh
events few months ago so there are
efforts ongoing to normalize relations
to a certain to whatever extent is
possible between India and China now the
Chinese are not doing this because they
have they've changed they had a change
of heart and they suddenly love us
they're doing it because they're
pragmatic they're practical the US
market is now going to be very soon off
limits to them because of Trades and
tariffs Trump will make sure of that the
EU will do whatever Trump says so which
other big Market does he have left
Africa is not a market Russia is not
that big of an economy or Market the
only big giant market left is India so
China will need to normalize relations
with us to be able to export their stuff
to our Market that's what they want
otherwise they they have nowhere to
export to that's the problem now the
Americans now Trump definitely wants to
put a lid and curbs on
China China is the big adversary he is
the guy after Decades of China policies
to start the trade war against China he
is the first
president since the
1960s to reverse US policy on China and
go all out in a trade war against China
and now he's back so his objective will
be to contain China and India is the
lynchpin in this he can't tell Russia to
to stop dealing with China but he can
certainly de tell
us we are a much smaller
Nation our hard power is 12th of the U
125th of the US
almost 120th of the US so they can
definitely arm twist us and there's
nothing we can do about it so um it'll
be dicey between us and China uh it
depends on on various factors it depends
on how well Mr Modi negotiates he's a
definitely a great negotiator Mr Modi
tough negotiator and if he's able to
negotiate it right then we may even be
able to have a good relationship Rel
relatively with the Chinese so the next
four years are going to be very
interesting a
lot of unknown parameters exist right
now not really unknown but hidden
parameters it's like things being in a
Quantum superp position even this is
possible even that is possible multiple
things are possible at the same time it
all depends on which way the the Box is
open and whether the cat is dead or
alive that sort of thing so yeah the
next four years are going to be uh
difficult they're going to be very
interesting but I think Mr Modi is a
great negotiator and he has a great
equation and relationship with Mr Trump
so I'm sure we'll work things out in a
way that's beneficial for us and our
relationship with relationships with
various
Nations okay multiple questions about
Manipur T Supremacy Anamika Verma Dian
di okay
danana and Grim so bad Manipur CM Mr bin
sing resigned what will happen now tell
us about Manipur first the CM resigned
and then after meeting with the home
minister and now after four days
president's rule has been imposed on the
PM is in the US and is there any
understanding between India and the US
CIA uh just before Modi meeting Trump uh
president's rules imposed in Manipur do
you think some sort of deal has been
struck with Trump since Modi G is in the
US so this problem can finally be
tackled and the US won't interfere and
stop arming the cookies
uh finally SAR after two years
presidential rule has been finally
imposed Manipur everything seems to be
well planned from the resignation of the
chief minister no elections for the next
eight months us Aid gone for a toss
appointing Mr Ajay Kumar Bish as the new
governor all the way to Trump Modi visit
it seems a lot of planning has gone into
it how do you see the rapid development
and where do you see this going uh I
think the dismantling of us Aid is a
positive step for sure uh it's clear to
me that there must have been some uh
behind the scenes uh discussions uh
dealings negotiations Etc maybe
agreements between India and the Trump
Administration uh after Mr Trump took
oath of
office uh and this must have definitely
uh involved the discussion of Manipur
I'm pretty certain of that obviously
none of this has been made public if it
has happened I'm speculating but this is
called an educated guess because of
things the way things happen so Trump is
in power Trump has taken office just
like two three weeks ago uh less than a
month ago right less than a month ago
and lots has already happened so Mr
Beren Singh Is asked to resign look Mr
Beren Singh despite him being the chief
minister the past two years it was defao
presidential rule anyway so he has
resigned
now and
uh the assembly hasn't been dissolved it
has been suspended so all the mlas are
they remain in place but they don't
really have any executive powers right
now um so This president's rule Mr Beren
Singh Is Now tweeting and revealing
certain things on Twitter which on onx
which are very
interesting uh now why do we talk about
Manipur with the Americans because the
whole problem was created by the
Americans just like Bangladesh the
regime change was a deep State
orchestrated coup what is happening in
Manipur is not some local Law and Order
situation it is a geopolitical
matter and look I have discussed this in
great detail the issue the core issue in
Manipur is the presence of hundreds of
thousands of foreigners on Indian
Territory they are squatting on more
than half of manipur's territory
foreigners who have crossed the open
border from
Burma and there a civil war going on in
Burma right now lots of various ethnic
groups fighting the government and
fighting each other some of them are
together some of them are together
because they're held together by the by
the by the church and when the church is
there you have deep State and the church
is one of the most powerful
organizations in the Far East of India
the so-called Northeast of
India and the cookies are these days
Christians some of them are also Jews
despite being fond of pork so the the
real problem the core issue in Manipur
is the illegal infiltration of lacks of
cookis into India from Burma them
setting up villages on manipuri
territory and now apparently and they
have AAR cards and and various
documentation and they are now claiming
to be Indians and Indigenous and the
true indigenous people of Manipur are
the nagas and the mes and the mes are
confined to like 5% 6% of the historical
territory of Manipur they're confined
there by law and the cookies can go
whever they want and they're unleashing
Mayhem Mayhem man that's the issue and
where does the endless supply of arms
and ammunition come from for the
cookies right and mizoram is a big
factor in this allegedly allegedly many
significant percentage of the illegal
infil infiltrators is allegedly being
brought in from mizoram and then being
pushed into Manipur allegedly so mizoram
is also a big
issue and all of this behind all of this
you
have whatever you want to call it the
Deep State the
CIA it's the US establishment and this
is the objective is to is to create an
artificial Christian Nation out of parts
of India Manipur mizoram out of parts of
Burma and out of part of Bangladesh and
sheikina has had revealed this she had
she she had revealed This months many
months before she was Ed so where a
prime minister makes this disclosure you
got to take it
seriously um and and what we see on the
ground is exactly that happening the
attempt to create an artificial
Christian Nation cookie land for
Christ and these cookies they don't even
have any allegiance to
Burma that's a deal so that's why if you
want to resolve the issue or start
resolving the issue you have to
negotiate with the
Americans so what's going to happen now
is the question right where do I see
this going I not sure right now like
like when you have leverage over a
nation you don't give it up money is
such a big pain point for India right
now our people are suffering Indian
citizens
right it's a
huge uh blot so to say on the record of
the Modi government
clearly um so it's it's a huge very
powerful leverage they have over us they
can squeeze us anytime they want by
ratcheting up us up the violence in
Manipur if they want to I mean the
capital of Manipur imagine the capital
city of a state is bombed by drones by
terrorists by Foreign terrorists that's
what happened that's been what's been
happening in in Manipur so uh I think
it'll be I'll be surprised if the
Americans give up whatever leverage they
have over money
and even if they give it up and we start
fixing the issue we'll have to deport
lacks of foreign infiltrators from
Manipur then we will have to do a CAA
kind of thing and establish exactly who
are the indigenous people and who are
the illegal infiltrators and descendants
of illegal infiltrators it's going to be
a long process this fixing this
mess that goes back a century and a half
is going to take at least 20 years
and those 20 years are going to be
painful for one for
Manipur so uh yeah it would be nice to
have an very quick resolution of the
problem but the problem the core problem
is that lacks of foreigners have taken
over Manipur territory Indian Territory
and another Indian State allegedly is
allegedly helping these alleged
infiltrators
allegedly so these are deep rooted
issues and uh clearly there have been
intelligence failures on our part
and The Roots goes roots of the issues
go back to the British times and post
Independence we continued the practice
of bringing in illegal cookies into
India and settling them only in
Manipur so a lot of people are culpable
in this but the the end result is that
Manipur suffers the indigenous natives
of Manipur
suffer
and there were clashes between the nagas
and the cookis in the 1990s it was a
civil war kind of
situation and clearly the government of
India and successive governments learned
nothing from that and now you have a
state of
Siege a state of Siege Civil War kind of
situation again so I don't see any
immediate or quick resolution of the
problem if we start addressing the
problem now it may take at least 10 20
years okay PR Paul says what's your view
on President Trump's comment about
Palestinians being permanently relocated
to Jordan and Egypt and the implications
it might have on the ongoing conflict in
Gaza will the US really cap Gaza as they
suggested the Americans will do whatever
they
want and if this is done what Trump is
suggesting that's a permanent resolution
to the to the Gaza issue you take the
gazans out of Gaza distribute them
across various countries Egypt Jordan
some in Saudi Arabia some in UA the rest
in Indonesia Gaza is empty of
gazans of the people and then you can
redevelop it and build casinos and what
not you want and make it a holiday
spot Trump is imminently capable of
making this happen so what and he wants
to make this happen and Netanyahu is on
board with this plan so what happens now
the the Israeli Armed
Forces
IDF will now what's what's a decent word
to use term to use sanitize is sanitize
a good word to use they will sanitize
Gaza which means they will
um tackle let's say address neutralize
the terrorists
Hamas and then they will evict the the
locals and they will be shipped off to
the various countries and that will be
the end of
it um and apparently Nations like Egypt
Jordan and other nations have agreed to
to to absorb various numbers of uh Gaza
residents so I think it's going to
happen it's it's it's going to happen I
don't think there's going to be too much
opposition to this um as long as the as
the Gaza as the people of Gaza get to
live in better places and live a
peaceful life I don't think anybody will
be upset with this sort of um uh
solution to the matter so it looks like
it's going to happen and it looks like
it could be a viable uh solution
long-term permanent solution to this uh
issue the Gaza
issue um hatim Lala says do the bricks
Nations have the ability to build or
create their own currency because during
the bilateral meeting between PM Modi
and president Trump Mr Trump said they
would impose 100% tariff tariffs on
bricks Nations if they try to mess with
the dollar and uh try to mess with the
hegemony of the US
dollar what what's going to happen right
um
I think it's um I don't see a bricks
currency happening anytime soon first of
all India has made it very clear that we
are not interested in a bricks currency
and if a bricks currency happens we will
not be part of it so if India is not
part of it then what it's only China and
Russia that's left right and the other
nations aren't that important or
economies of any any any size compared
to let's say India so uh without India
participating in the bricks currency
bricks C bricks currency can't really
work and I don't think it makes sense to
have bricks currency right now what the
bricks nations are doing right now is
they
prioritizing um trade in local
currencies rupee Ruble trade Ruble Yuan
trade Yuan rupe and and whatever else
Duram uh Ruble
whatever uh that sort of thing um so
that I think is a is a much better
viable option as opposed to cre creating
a bricks
currency and Trump is is is very anti-
bricks he sees bricks as a as a threat
to the US dollar the he sees it as a
threat to the hegemony of the US dollar
and he obviously will
um he obviously will not support that so
I don't think it makes sense for us
to to try and displease him so I don't
think a bricks currency is coming
anytime soon
Jagdish Mali says was is um sorry is
there ever a possibility of a world
government given the US potentially
reaching hyper power status from being a
superpower and the rapidly changing
geopolitical
scenario a world
government um look you
see in the 20th
century uh Edward lutwak
published a book about Imperial Rome the
grand strategy of Rome or something it
was
called and Edward lutwak is is one of
the most respected geost strategists in
the world right now right now today and
he's appeared on my podcast you can see
it uh on this channel so in the 20th
century Edward lutwak published this
book about uh RS Imperial Rome's
geopolitical
strategy and in this book he
distinguished between two kinds of
Empires
territorial Empires and hegemonic
Empires so territorial Empires they
directly occupy territories with their
armies they put armies in the territory
of the nation they occupy they
physically occupy the Nations by
building military bases on the in the
nation and having the troops in in the
nation and sometimes they throw out the
old rulers and Annex the land that's a
territorial Empire
in a hegemonic Empire the internal
affairs of the conquered Nations and
areas remain in the hands of the
original rulers who become
vasal so territorial Empires are tightly
controlled but very costly to maintain
because you have to maintain these
military bases you to maintain large
numbers of soldiers you to supply them
and you to make sure there is no and
problems in the host nation very
difficult to maintain and operate but a
hegemonic Empire are inexpensive to
maintain because the original local
rulers they incur the costs of
administration and everybody's going to
blame them you can invisibly control a
country like this so the United
States is a hegemonic Empire mostly they
do occupy some Nations like Japan and
Germany and South Korea and on so on uh
but overall the rest of the world with
whether it is the NATO Nations EU
Nations African nations they have very
distant control hegemonic
control um so in a hegemonic Empire
there is a lose tie a lose rather
invisible tie between master and vasal
and this can sometimes encourage
rebellion and that's why you have katas
in in Africa and so on so every Conquest
minded Empire is a
mixture of hegemonic Empire and
territorial Empire some are 80%
Territorial and 2 20% hegemonic some
some are 80% hegemonic 20% territorial
Etc the US is mainly a hegemonic Empire
okay now uh let's say that the US
becomes a hyper power how does the US
become a hyper power through space
exploration colonizing Mars and the moon
and secondly through
AI so AI permeates the whole world
people don't even realize that the world
becomes a monoculture because you are
getting a very individually tailored
experience of what news you watch what
music is served to you uh what
entertainment is given to you through OT
platforms it looks so unique and
distinct to what everybody else gets so
you feel that you are being
empowered but within all that variance
there is a monoculture that is being
established across the world and AI can
help a hegemonic power to control the
whole world without the world realizing
it so that's
about that could be about to happen
right uh but if that happens there is no
need of a world one world government
because all the governments anyway will
will tow your line without realizing it
or with by realizing it so uh eii will
make it happen we eii could create an
invisible Global
government in which Every Nation
just TOS the line of the US and the
people of the nation don't even realize
it that's already been the case in the
EU the EU is a bunch of a large number
of
nations that have lost their
sovereignty it's already a one
government from Brussels why do I say
they've lost their sovereignty what are
the characteristics or Hallmarks of
Sovereign Nation you control your
borders and you control your
currency the EU Nations don't control
their borders their borders are open
they don't even have the ceny they have
to use the E the the Euro which is a
rebranded deut
mark so there is no and thirdly
Sovereign Nation passes its own laws in
the EU they can't even pass their laws
they have to agree to the laws from
Brussels the EU has lost its sovereignty
it's already a one government and the
same could happen eventually across the
world because of AI whether the these
nations like it or not so it could
happen could happen
soon pram sh says what are your views on
the AI Summit I found vice president J
JD W's speech quite confrontational to
say the least towards not just China but
also France and the US and UK obviously
did not sign the joint statement I also
notice that maon gave India an
extraordinary reception also joining PM
during departure is this a Nuance
country is consider did France and India
try to put some pressure back on the US
so I haven't really uh I haven't really
looked in detail at the AI Summit uh
Vance he has given some pretty
confrontational speeches uh recently he
he has he's on a mission to scold the EU
scold the EU to lecture the EU to
excoriate the European
Union uh ma definitely gave the PM as
always a great reception uh France is
like I keep saying the only EU Nation
NATO nation that has a quasi independent
foreign policy completely independent
Sovereign nuclear um
option and France wants great relations
with India to bolster its sovereignty
and and U and its uh and the safe the
Safety and Security of its Indian Ocean
possessions now the the speech by Vance
was quite something so he gave us he
says that the greatest threat threat to
Europe is an internal threat not an
external threat and it's from a threat
it's a threat from fundamental values
like democracy and free speech so the EU
is now deprioritizing democracy in free
speech and he said that elections are
being annuled and free expression is
being curtailed and stifled and people
are being jailed uh for for social media
posts and there is talk of countering
misinformation and and hate speech they
are you know killing democracy in under
this
pretext and he said that in the cold
during the Cold War various auth
authoritarian Nations we're doing the
same thing so how are you different from
these nations right that's what he was
saying and uh social media obviously the
the curement of social media and he
speaks about Germany and U he talks
about Sweden and he speak he gave
various examples UK also a person he was
praying near an abortion clinic was
arrested uh and
prosecuted and so on um and he did
acknowledge that the previous
administration the Biden Administration
did encourage the EU uh to do this and
they did go after social media but he
said that the Trump Administration will
be different and we're going to protect
free expression and all that we're going
to Champion free speech he spoke about
the analment of Romania's election which
is like essentially alarming you
essentially stifling destroying
democracy and he said that democracy is
it so fragile that it can be destroyed
by limited amounts of alleged foreign
interference or influence or advertising
obviously he's referring to musk because
musk has been trying to interfere in
Germany's election recently and populist
or or right-wing parties are being
excluded from various things and all so
you're you're dismissing opposing views
to whatever your views are so where's
the Democracy in this and then obviously
he spoke about migration Mass migration
he said that there's large scale
immigration that's been done into Europe
and U it's causing all kinds of problems
in Europe social tension and uh violent
incidents obviously are on the rise and
you know the voters in Europe have not
agreed to open the
floodgates uh and so on so he said that
you know all these things are completely
wrong completely undemocratic you are
becoming intolerant you're becoming
undemocratic you're becoming
censorious you're censoring the people
uh you are undermining their
concerns and so
on and and anything you say if the
government doesn't like it it's
misinformation so he really
piled on all this and and scolded the
EU and yeah that's what it was so looks
like the US is is now going to
completely
reorient the EU the EU Nations and the
way they operate right now there is
resistance from the EU Nations VAV the
Ukraine settlement that's going to
happen and other issues but they're
going to bring them to heal the EU is
going to have to do what they're told so
there you have it yes
uh V says why is Ireland not part of the
five eyes intelligence Network group
even though they check all the criterias
the English speakers white ethnicity
Christians not a threat to the
currencies order by the US well they are
not English speakers the indigenous
language of Ireland is Irish
gallic and it's a it's a language that's
been wiped out by the imposition of
English so let's take a look at uh the
map of Ireland to understand the
situation Ireland well this may be a
surprise to some of you but Ireland is a
partitioned Nation Northern Ireland is
British occupied
Ireland and southern Ireland is
nominally independent of
Britain and there Ireland fought for its
freedom for
decades they fought against British
occupation for
decades in a period called the
troubles and I'll not go into the
history of that but they fought against
the anglos they are not anglos the
English people the people of
England um they are a mixture of
Anglo-Saxons and
Normans the Anglo-Saxons invaded the
islands in the middle of the first
Millennium ad
and the Anglo Saxons came from ger
present day Germany parts of present day
Germany so there are Germanic people and
the vi and and the Normans were also a
Germanic people who spoke French but
they had their they had been given land
in in in Fr in present day France by the
then King of
France uh in exchange for protection
against Viking raids despite themselves
being Vikings so the Anglo-Saxons and
and the Normans are the stock that makes
up the englishspeaking
people the Irish people the Scottish
people are not Anglo-Saxons or Normans
or or Nordic people they are Kelts they
are of Celtic stock they're different
they were discriminated against horribly
by the by the
anglos and in the US they were not even
considered whites for a long
time uh so it's a different ethnicity
and they are not English speakers yeah
they're Christians but many of them are
Catholics not Protestants that's problem
isn't it and they fought the anglos for
a very long time and even today they may
have aspirations of freedom from British
occupation so that's why they're not
part of the five eyes uh
Coalition and also because they're not
powerful in their own right and because
Ireland southern Ireland nominally an
indep nation has multiple US military
bases on its territory which means it's
it's actually technically in the US
occupation so then why do you need it to
be so it's it's not really a Sovereign
Nation but neither is the UK or
Australia or New Zealand or Canada but
Ireland isn't that powerful or important
or large or whatever so that's why it's
not part of the five eyes grouping of
Nations McLovin PR Paul Slim Shady
Supreme Court said it will pass order
with the center in Delhi government to
Grant access to school admissions for
children of rohinga refugees are we
following Europe have you already become
a vasal with the Supreme Court asserting
that no child will be discriminated
against uh regarding rohinga access to
public schools what broader implications
does this have for India's immigration
policies and National Security C this
set a president for further
legitimization of illegal settlements
recently the Supreme Court has suggested
the government provide Healthcare
facilities education AC accommodation
allegedly possibly for ringas are they
out of their minds is it so difficult to
understand that the Indian taxpayer
resources are for Indians and not for
aliens is it so difficult to understand
that these people are a threat to threat
to National
Security they will destroy the social
fabric of the country why are we always
lectured to take the moral High Ground
please share your views
okay yeah it is a surprising um
order and it's obviously going to happen
at at the expense of the Indian taxpayer
the education for the children of
illegal
infiltrators so I think uh the
government needs to take some actions
okay you cannot go against what the
Supreme Court has done apparently you
can't if if the government you do what
the Supreme Court says but what the
government can do it can pass laws uh
see right now Trump is deporting
illegal Indian immigrants to the US
they're sending them back in Chains
right so this is a great time for us to
get rid of our illegal immigrants so
let's say the Supreme Court says okay
that we should give provide education
and Healthcare and whatever else fine
but it doesn't say that we cannot Deport
them so the government should pass a law
or whatever is required legally properly
done that enables us it gives us a
framework to to deport illegal aliens
who have entered the country illegally
there by being in the country illegally
you are a criminal actually and
criminals
aren't aren't supposed to be given
privileges that Indians many Indians
don't get free education and all so the
government needs to act fast as soon as
possible and create a legal framework to
deport all the illegal ringas all the
illegal Bangladesh's Etc because
otherwise it's going to be a huge burden
on the Indian taxpayer it's already a
huge burden but now you're going to be
educating the children
of
criminals and by educating them you're
making them Indians and then and then
they will claim that we we have been
educated India we've lived in India we
deserve Indian citizenship and and it's
going to cause a lot of problems
Downstream and if we don't Deport these
people it's going to have tremendous
delerious effects on India's uh National
Security like you saying and it could
then give rise to further PS forther
legitimization of illegal settlers and
that and and giving them citizenship or
Asylum or whatever so the government
needs to act as fast as possible that's
what I would say because this is this
situation is
untenable it's it's a national security
threat for
us right Rik power says if the UK were
not an island country would the painter
have taken the UK in six weeks just like
he did with France what's your
[Laughter]
take uh Second World War
uh map we talking about the second world
war here and the painter is you know the
painter
right the Austrian painter
so so the UK is an island country isn't
it and uh Hitler was able to take the
painter Hitler was able to take France
very rapidly he was able to steamroll
most of Europe just Blitz cre through
all the defenses the majino line and all
that and take all the nations the reason
he could not take the it was so much
more difficult to take the UK was
because it was across the the English
Channel right and uh he would have had
to uh to create an invasion Fleet and
plan this properly for for months uh
just like William the Conqueror did in
the year 1066 and the UK would have been
ready for it and that's why they instead
went with the doodle Bugs the the V1 V2
uh missiles and uh the Battle of London
happened between
F wolfes and mids and Spitfires and so
on so because you the UK was an island
that's why it was so much more difficult
for the
painter to conquer
it and eventually he decided
to set the UK aside for a while and
instead do operation Barbarosa which led
to his undoing eventual undoing
initially it was a great success he his
troops were able to have Moscow in their
in their sides in binocular
but eventually the tide turned and so on
so yeah if the UK was not an island
country the painter would have taken it
very rapidly for
sure uh Vikram says after the recent
Modi Trump meeting it looks like India
is becoming a vasal of the US is this
true okay how do we Define
aasal
aasal is a nation that
U see examples of vasal all the EU
nations are vasal of the US all the NATO
nations are vasal of the US how have the
EU EU Nations been made vasal of the US
they have been deprived of their
sovereignty they don't control their
borders they don't control their
currency they don't control their
economy they don't control their laws
it's all controlled from Brussels and
Brussels is controlled by the US in a
variety of ways and then there are the
NATO Nations which have again pooled
sovereignty and their armed forces are
under the Central Command and the and
the Central Command is controlled by the
US so that's how we deprive a nation of
sovereign and make it make it your wasal
or you can have physical occupation like
Japan South Korea Etc and so on now
India is not in any of those situations
yes the US is powerful Su super powerful
and if they demand something we have to
do it but it doesn't mean we are it
means that we are in an in a weaker
position which we are we are not in the
same league as the US forget about the
us we're not not in the same league as
Russia or
China but we need the us on our side
because of the complicated world we live
in especially the Chinese
threat um but we can counterbalance the
US with China and Russia especially
Russia so it's complicated and when you
have these options at your disposal
you're not AAL when you don't have the
presence of US military bases and troops
on your soil you're not vasal when the
US doesn't control your economy or your
Borders or your currency or your laws
you're not AAL so yeah we are definitely
in a weaker position and the US can
certainly
arm twist us if if they want to but they
also don't want to do it Beyond a limit
because then they will throw they will
push us into the arms of Russia or China
so it's a delicate game that we are
playing but we are by no means a usal
and even if we become a vasal well it'll
be great for the citizens of India
because a lot of the world will open up
to you all
so so do not
despair okay uh I think I've I have
finished with the questions I had
selected let's take some questions from
the live
chat uh let's take
some questions from the live chat
um okay Amisha says ranir again posted
that he is he and his family are being
threatened it's very sad it's terrible
you know we are a very emotional people
our public is extremely emotional and
it's so easy to to play just like an
orchestra and and and if you have a big
platform if you have a big TV network or
whatever and if you're jealous of run
and you feel threatened by his success
then when something like this happens
you can really play on the emotions of
the Indians and make them all hate him
by trending hashtags and whatnot uh so
we Indian emotional Indians will then go
and say stupid things and probably abuse
him and threaten him in his family it's
it's very sad we are not a mature people
we are not a serious people
and it's not our fault I don't blame the
Indian public the education system has
ensured that they their minds have been
destroyed and they can't think straight
they don't have the ability to think
critically and I've been saying for so
long we need to reform the education
system not a thing is being done so
overall it's it's just sad it's it's
really sad this whole matter there are
so many huge problems in India today and
we are busy doing this leave the man
alone he made a mistake he is suffering
and he's paying for it he has not harmed
anyone he did something very stupid his
words were
crass they definitely were unacceptable
and very
disappointing but much worse is out
there and at least he he has done so
much good also through his work and he's
not an anti-national unlike some other
people so leave the guy alone man enough
enough
okay buja s says every personal is
emotional if anyone doesn't have
emotions he's a God not a person anymore
LOL sir you have put forth a profound
truth here despite saying LOL everybody
has
emotions every person has the same
emotions as the other person we are all
born with emotions our em emotions are
an evolutionary
trait they serve a purpose in the
survival of the fittest everybody has
emotions but to succeed in
life you don't kill your
emotions you have to learn to control
your emotions people who are controlled
by their emotions never succeed in life
people who Master their emotions
succeed if there is a storm around you
everything is going wrong and you just
fall apart and start crying and
panicking you will never
succeed but if you are strong enough to
master your emotions control your
emotions and during the worst time if
you are able to think clearly and do the
right things then you will succeed in
life no one is saying that you have to
be
unemotional be emotional everybody has
emotions learn to control
and master your emotions LOL
sir um
okay panel tripati says how are you able
to speak so eloquently you know for the
majority of my life I have not been a
speaker I have been a writer a person
who expresses himself in
writing I did not even know that I had
the ability to speak in
public until I started doing these live
streams do you know that I've never been
a public speaker until then but yeah you
know everybody has so many um let's say
qualities that they're not aware of so I
wasn't aware of this quality that I
could speak apparently eloquently I
wasn't aware of
this so my point is we all have
qualities and talents that we may not be
aware of and we will never know about
it if we don't put we will not know
about this if we never put ourselves in
uncomfortable situations or unfamiliar
situations if we never try something new
or if you never try something difficult
or something scary you will never truly
learn who you really are my point is
take chances do hard things do things
that scare you
it's fun try it out and you may discover
that you have talents that you had never
imagined go for
it
um Raj God says when's the new Edward
Luwak podcast coming would you like a
podcast with Mr L with Dr lutwak um I
don't know I could I could approach him
again uh nothing is planned th far but
yeah it's a good good suggestion I could
I could probably request him uh to
rejoin me for a podcast there's a lot to
discuss certainly
okay
um right what what what other questions
do we have uh lots of questions of
course AR says how do you use Rich
vocabulary well that I can answer very
clearly I've been reading all my
life I I could have been classified as
as a First Rate
nerd I mean as a kid one of one of the
you know the best way for me to spend my
day was the day in the library I was
that sort of kid even at the age of
seven the library was the best place for
me to go I could go at 9:00 a.m. in the
morning and leave at 9:00 p.m. in the
night I would read read read so if you
read so much you obviously going to pick
up lots of words lots of difficult words
unknown words some of the words stay in
your head but you don't know the meaning
some of the words you look up in the
dictionary so you learn what they are
then you learn how to use them so it's a
process so I was a nerdy kid the only
thing that thing that saved me from
being a nerd was that I was I loved
Sports and I was really good at that not
good at every sport but good at some
sports sports that needed strength and
brute strength and large size so so
that's that's what saved me from being a
nerd but yeah I was I read a lot so
that's how you acquire Rich vocabulary
by reading and by writing so you read
you acquire words and then by writing
you use the words and you get familiar
with
them Akay says when I use the word
allegedly four times that topic is
statistically
yeah that's right that's right I I would
agree with that Mansa says are you gonna
censor yourself in criticizing the US
now that India will have to work closely
with the US and listen to its deep State
no um
I have never said
anything um that crosses a
line Vis of the US there are people who
say who say really harsh and and and uh
rude things about the US I don't I have
my own analysis of of the geopolitical
uh power equations in the world the
balance of power I have my understanding
over a lifetime of study of how the US
works I'm I'm doing this new part right
now America understanding America in
which I'm revisiting the whole of my
understanding of the United States from
the very Basics from the very
foundations um so what I'm expressing
and and putting out putting forth is a
very realistic and very uh balanced view
of how things are and I'm sure the
Americans appreciate cander
frankness and a pragmatic realistic
worldview uh and obviously I'm not privy
to any privileged
information which could be a problem but
I am not I'm just whatever I know is
known from I I know it from open source
material so there is no question of
censoring
myself uh I will continue to express
myself um
freely
okay um um Anita says if India could
have a do Department Department of
governmental efficiency like what Trump
has installed for the US which
departments should be cut and
reorganized according to my view well
that's a pretty complicated and detailed
involved topic but
uh we are the one nation that does need
a department of governmental efficiency
there is so much bloat in our governance
mechanisms in our governance structures
what's bloat
unnecessary hiring people people who
don't need to be there one of the best
examples of
bloat is uh
drdo
drdo has
apparently last time I
saw 5,000 scientific personnel and
25,000 non-scientific Personnel my
question is what the hell are those
25,000 non-scientific personnel there
for
is one there to polish the shoes of
everybody is one there to give a
shoulder massage is somebody else there
to to put butter on bread what the hell
are 25,000 people there
for the government and the bureaucrats
have turned every organ of the
government into an employment generation
scheme there is so much bloat every
organ of governance is
bloated and
inefficient so you know I don't even
know where to start but yeah we need
that it's never going to happen because
the bureaucrats and and these non you
know this these people have a complete
veto or everything they control
everything strangle hold and if you do
if you take any steps against them
against towards cutting the bloat and
they're going to paralyze the whole
governance system they'll go on strike
so it's almost impossible for India at
this
stage for this to happen but everything
needs to cut be cut down to Sid is
everything every Department every organ
of government everything is problematic
in
India um
okay okay let's see some other questions
um Arijit says I'm from jamshedpur in
jarand and in our city each and every
vendor is a Bangladeshi every vegetable
shop cloth shop food shop Etc is being
run by this Bangladesh is
uh I don't even know what to say yeah we
know this we know this I don't know how
we have
allowed ourselves to to be in this
situation but it looks like there are
maybe a 100 million Bangladesh's in
India right
now all over the
place all over the
place it's it's
it's a very serious
situation then I I would appeal to the
government to to take steps to to end
this and what led to the situation also
needs to be looked at what is the role
of the the alleged role of the alleged B
BSF in this alleged
situation what is the role that the the
BSF may or may not have allegedly played
in this the border security force a
paramilitary force not the Indian
military lots of hard questions need to
be asked nobody is ever punished
for the treasonous allegedly treasonous
activities they allegedly
do terrible terrible situation and and
thank you Arijit for for for letting the
world know of what's happening in
jamshedpur
jhand what's the government
doing
okay you know people say that these days
have become rather
negative when these fact facts come to
light do you expect me to be dancing and
saying nice
things I I am not a negative person I'm
a very jolly person I'm a very
optimistic person but sometimes you have
these things what do you
do like sparkling Lotus says it's time
for swaj
again
okay sensei chavas
says India allegedly has 176 nuclear
warheads nukes I don't believe the
official counts by Nations as I think
they try to underplay their capab
abilities how many nukes could India and
the other powers truly have look IND if
you we have no idea of knowing how many
nukes a nation has when the West says
puts out a number set of numbers for
each Nation that's propaganda they have
no idea how many nukes we have how how
do they
know they're just guesstimating right
but we have some kind of understanding
of how much file material our nation
has file material is the weapons grade
uranium and weapons grade
plutonium how much of this do we have
well it takes less plutonium to have a
warhead to make a warhead compared to
uranium so plutonium is nicer to have so
if you add up how much file material we
have according to various studies we may
allegedly have enough file material for
3,000 4,000 nuclear warheads we India
okay
now if we have that much file material
will we have 176 nukes Warheads I don't
know maybe maybe we have disassembled
Warheads that we can assemble at in at
at 10 minutes notice and then we may
have 300 or more or more so there's no
way of knowing whatever numbers the West
puts out is propaganda that's it so I
don't know I can only tell you that we
have sufficient file material for maybe
3 or 4,000 nuclear weapons most likely
and that's based on Pakistani studies
and I don't have the studies right now
at my disposal it'll take time to look
for it but I have actually put it out in
in a previous episode A couple of years
ago so if you want you can look it
up okay let us take one final question
for the day and then we can wrap it up
for
today
um let us see let us see what is it
viang Sharma says is it possible to buy
both the F35 the so 57 my point my
question is why would you do
that why I mean do we have that much
money floating around we'll just throw
it at two different aircraft
systems it doesn't make sense okay so
we'll just buy one of these we'll buy
one of these because we have limited
money we need to throw money at the Lely
B Yoga and what other whatever other
freebies we giving right to our
voters so we only have limited money for
for defense so we got to be very careful
with this very
parsimonious with this money that we
have and with that I think I'm going to
end today's live stream at this point uh
thank you very much for all your
questions I'm sure many of you have so
many more questions but we'll we'll end
it for here today today for here next
weekend I probably am traveling so we
may not have a live stream next weekend
but uh
but but we we'll try and do something
about it maybe I'll do something from
wherever I'm traveling so uh yeah let's
wrap it up for you for today over here
thank you so much for all your questions
apologies to those of you whose
questions I could not take thank you
very much for your viewership I really
appreciate
it keep asking questions keep raising
your standards and I will see you next
time as soon as I can very soon take
care bye-